<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://bencatcraw.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://bencatcraw.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-16T01:17:38+00:00</updated><id>https://bencatcraw.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A game dev portfolio </subtitle><entry><title type="html">2026 is here!</title><link href="https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2026/newyear/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2026 is here!"/><published>2026-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2026/newyear</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2026/newyear/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="intro">Intro</h3> <p>Hi everyone, I’ve been super busy and totally forgot to stay updated with these posts. A lot has changed recently and I’m excited to share the latest and greatest of what I’ve done.</p> <h3 id="my-progress">My Progress</h3> <p>I’ve just started my second semester of my Masters in Computer Science, and I’ve tried to keep my course load relatively light so I have time to focus on game development. Last post, I talked about the future of Wizard Kart and Killcode 404, and while I’ve made significant progress on both since then, our focus at Studio 300 has recently shifted to working on a smaller project than Killcode 404 to experience the entire game pipeline and get our name out there sooner. We are now working on a coop dungeon crawler, which will utilize my skills for multiplayer, and so far is easier to iterate on as many of us are fond of fantasy settings. While I’m not quite ready to share screenshots/clips yet, because I want the game to be in a bit more polished state, what we already have so far is very promising and very motivating to work on.</p> <h3 id="games-im-playing">Games I’m Playing</h3> <p><strong>Core Keeper</strong> I tried Core Keeper for the first time after many reccomendations and was immediately hooked. I really enjoy the top down style of Core Keeper over the Terraria platformer angle. My friends and I easily put 30 hours in within a week, and still have a lot to do, explore, and fight. While we haven’t finished the game, I can safely say I definitely reccomend it, especially to those who love Terraria as I think it offers a similar experience in terms of exploration and progression.</p> <p><strong>Far Far West Playtest</strong> I spent some recent time with the Far Far West playtest after seeing it on social media, and have found it to be a very fun, very silly, take on the “Helldivers” genre. I am really suprised with the polish on an “alpha” playtest, and I’m excited for the full release.</p> <p><strong>Kingdom Come Deliverance 2</strong> I’ve just started KCD2, and while I usually struggle to finish these long open world games as I get stuck trying to do every side quest, this game has really pulled me in with its strong narrative, and at times feels more like I’m watching a show rather than playing a game.</p> <p>Thanks for reading, Ben</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[plans for 2026]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">first blog post</title><link href="https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2025/first/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="first blog post"/><published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2025/first</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2025/first/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone. I thought with the redesign of my portfolio I could incorporate a blog section, so I could write about my journey as a game developer, and even include some tutorials for stuff I’ve already created. (It’s also a good excuse to improve my writing skills)</p> <p>This redesign was inspired by seeing some other creative game developer portfolios. Because I did not want to build the website from the ground up, im using <strong><a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/tree/main">this</a></strong> very well made template as a starting place.</p> <p>Currently, I am focused on two main projects: Wizard Kart, an arcade racer and a spiritual successor to Wheelchair Wizards. Wizard Kart has large scope, but I hope to get a early alpha build out to test with friends to make sure its a viable project moving forward. The other project I’m working on is Killcode 404, a story driven cyberpunk shooter. I am the lead programmer for the project and I’ve mostly been spending my time flushing out enemies, as they are one of the most important elements in the shooter genre.</p> <p>As for games I’ve been playing recently, Arc Raiders has been at the top of the list. My friends and I had been waiting a long time since the first technical test we got access to, so naturally we’ve already put a lot of hours into the game. I’m really impressed with what Embark has done, and I’m excited for future updates. Other than that, I haven’t had too much time on my hands to play other PC games, but I have been enjoying Clash Royale’s take on autobattlers: Merge Tactics. I’ve found because the games are much faster, it’s much easier to pick up and play compared to sitting down for a full 30+ minute TFT game. It also has much simpler rules, so I don’t feel like I have to keep up with the meta like I do for TFT.</p> <p>That’s all for now, hopefully I’ll be back soon with more.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[introductory blog post]]></summary></entry></feed>