<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://bencatcraw.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://bencatcraw.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-08T08:44:45+00:00</updated><id>https://bencatcraw.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A game dev portfolio </subtitle><entry><title type="html">first blog post</title><link href="https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2025/first/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="first blog post"/><published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2025/first</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bencatcraw.github.io/blog/2025/first/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone. I thought with the redesign of my portfolio I could incorporate a blog section, so I could write about my journey as a game developer, and even include some tutorials for stuff I’ve already created. (It’s also a good excuse to improve my writing skills)</p> <p>This redesign was inspired by seeing some other creative game developer portfolios. Because I did not want to build the website from the ground up, im using <strong><a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/tree/main">this</a></strong> very well made template as a starting place.</p> <p>Currently, I am focused on two main projects: Wizard Kart, an arcade racer and a spiritual successor to Wheelchair Wizards. Wizard Kart has large scope, but I hope to get a early alpha build out to test with friends to make sure its a viable project moving forward. The other project I’m working on is Killcode 404, a story driven cyberpunk shooter. I am the lead programmer for the project and I’ve mostly been spending my time flushing out enemies, as they are one of the most important elements in the shooter genre.</p> <p>As for games I’ve been playing recently, Arc Raiders has been at the top of the list. My friends and I had been waiting a long time since the first technical test we got access to, so naturally we’ve already put a lot of hours into the game. I’m really impressed with what Embark has done, and I’m excited for future updates. Other than that, I haven’t had too much time on my hands to play other PC games, but I have been enjoying Clash Royale’s take on autobattlers: Merge Tactics. I’ve found because the games are much faster, it’s much easier to pick up and play compared to sitting down for a full 30+ minute TFT game. It also has much simpler rules, so I don’t feel like I have to keep up with the meta like I do for TFT.</p> <p>That’s all for now, hopefully I’ll be back soon with more.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[introductory blog post]]></summary></entry></feed>